hi spring fans welcome to northern storm
嗨，春季球迷们欢迎来到北风暴
of spring tips in this installment we're
在这一期的 spring 技巧 中，我们是
going to look at flowable a BPMN
要看可流动的BPMN
compatible workflow engine that does so
兼容的工作流引擎
much more than just bpmn and now I don't
不只是bpmn，现在我不
even know where to start this is
甚至不知道从哪里开始
actually one of those things where I
实际上是我其中的一件事
think this installment this particular
认为这部分特别
video will just be one of a series
视频只是其中的一个
because I could really I could talk
因为我真的可以说话
about this stuff you know forever
关于你永远知道的东西
there's just so many different things to
有太多不同的事情要
talk about here um first of all let's
首先在这里谈谈
talk about what we're trying to do here
谈论我们在这里想要做什么
what the use case is here now in
用例现在在这里
previous installments we've looked at
我们看过的前几期
things like spring integration and
诸如Spring Integration和
spring batch in spring integration you
Spring Batch处理中的Spring Batch处理
are connecting systems to each other in
正在将系统彼此连接
terms of the events these events are
这些事件的事件术语是
born of real-life events in the real
真实生活中的现实事件
world and from that those events from
世界，从这些事件
the flow of event in from one system to
事件从一个系统流向
another you imply state use you can you
另一个你暗示状态使用你可以
can draw a picture that shows that data
可以画一张图来显示数据
moves through the system from one point
从一点移动通过系统
to another and eventually arrives at a
到另一个，最终到达
at a destination that's one way to look
在目的地是一种看待方式
at the world you're implying state where
在这个世界上，你暗示着
where there is no sort of world world
没有世界的世界
view of that state you're drawing a
该状态的视图，您正在绘制
picture of of otherwise disconnected
否则已断开连接的图片
systems and so that's that's one way to
系统，这就是
to architect the system on the other
在其他方面构建系统
hand some use cases some workloads some
处理一些用例，一些工作量
scenarios require that you have the
方案要求您具有
ability to actually lay proverbial hands
实际举起双手的能力
on that state to be able to audit it to
在该州能够对其进行审核
be able to look at the history of it to
能够看看它的历史
to be able to a query it right and in
能够正确查询
this case it's not just enough to look
这种情况不仅仅看起来
at the result of the movement of
在运动的结果
messages of the result of movement of
运动结果的信息
data through a system and then say this
数据通过系统，然后这样说
happened instead we need to be able to
发生了，相反，我们需要能够
say how far along are we what what
说我们走了多远
remains to be done and then more to the
有待完成，然后更多
point when you start getting into these
点，当你开始进入这些
kinds of sort of state intense and
那种状态紧张和
sometimes long-running
有时长时间运行
use cases as often it's not it's not
用例通常不是
just automatic sort of autonomous agents
只是自动排序的自治代理
that are involved in the process instead
该过程中涉及的
you
您
so got as likely as not human actors
因此获得的可能性不及人类演员
human agents that are involved in the
参与
system or that are involved in moving
系统或涉及移动
the work forward and so what we need is
前进的工作，所以我们需要的是
some way in these sort of more
在某种程度上更多
sophisticated scenarios of which there
有复杂的场景
are an infinite many you might in a
你可能有无数的
common one is insurance claims another
常见的一种是保险理赔
one is a sign up form right think about
一个是注册表格，请仔细考虑
insurance claims you've got somebody who
保险要求您有某人
wants to buy insurance but of course
想买保险，但是当然
there's a process in place a business
有一个业务流程
process that helps to capture the the it
帮助捕获它的过程
helps validate those who are applying
帮助验证正在申请的人
for insurance they they go through this
为了保险，他们经历了
process where then their background is
然后他们的背景是
checked their health is checked their
检查他们的健康检查他们
their finances are checked and they the
他们的财务状况得到检查，他们
organization does a risk assessment and
组织进行风险评估，
based on this they're able to sort of
基于此，他们能够
arrive at a price that the main they can
以他们可以买到的主要价​​格
then afford to sell the insurance or in
然后买得起保险或在
some cases not afford to sell insurance
在某些情况下买不起保险
right and this process is multi-step and
对，这个过程是多步骤的，
a lot of times it might be just very
很多时候可能只是
simple might be like oh well this person
很简单，就像这个人哦
is you know young and and healthy and no
你知道年轻健康吗？
problems at all and good money you know
根本没有问题，而且你知道钱不错
good credit card check and all that
好的信用卡支票等等
stuff so we can just go ahead and
东西，所以我们可以继续
approve that person right away on the
立即批准该人
other hand there might be some
另一方面可能会有一些
situations that require more extensive
需要更广泛的情况
sort of revision more extensive research
修订范围更广泛的研究
into the the case or into the claims or
案件或索赔中
whatever so in this case you might have
无论如何，在这种情况下，您可能会有
a human being that needs to actually to
一个需要实际去做的人
talk to somebody there might need to
与某人交谈，可能需要
make a phone call they might need to
打个电话，他们可能需要
talk to the applicant and this process
与申请人讨论此过程
is more involved but it involves human
参与更多但涉及人类
actors and this might require even
演员，这可能甚至需要
further still more work to be done right
进一步做正确的工作
it might actually create new processes
实际上可能会创建新流程
that get spun up in order to be able to
为了能够
arrive at a sort of a risk assessment
进行某种风险评估
result so this long written process
结果如此漫长的书面过程
hopefully arrives at a go or no-go
希望到达或不去
decision and at that point then you have
决定，那时候你有
a whole number of other things that need
大量其他需要的东西
to happen you send an email to the
碰巧，您发送电子邮件至
applicant before informing him or her of
申请人在通知他或她之前
the result of the decision to you know
你知道的决定结果
confirm insurance on that person you
为您确认该人的保险
send the email you wait for the
发送您等待的电子邮件
person to sign up to continue their
签约的人继续他们的
signup process you send another email
注册过程中，您发送另一封电子邮件
you wait for that person to click a
您等待那个人点击
document or click a link verifying their
文档或单击链接以验证其
email you give them an account on a
给您发电子邮件给他们一个帐户
website you have to print out cards you
网站您必须打印出卡片
know all these things all these long
这么久都知道
running steps and you don't you don't
运行步骤，你不，你不
know just by looking at the profile
只看个人资料就知道
table whether the process is done right
表该过程是否正确完成
and you really do need to know that you
你真的需要知道你
do need to know that somebody has done a
确实需要知道有人做了一个
background check you really do need to
您确实需要进行的背景调查
know that this person has been given
知道这个人已经被给予
their insurance policy documents and
他们的保险单文件和
everything's been signed and somebody's
一切都已经签名，有人
crossed all the T's and dotted all the
越过所有T并点缀所有
i's and and that the user has created a
我是并且用户已经创建了一个
profile on the website and you know all
个人资料在网站上，您知道所有
these things all these things have to
这些东西所有这些东西必须
happen before the exchange the
发生在交换之前
interaction oh of course you need to
互动当然，您需要
collect money right all these things
所有这些东西都收钱
have to happen before you can say your
必须先发生，然后才能说出您的
gun that the result of the of the
枪的结果
agreement has been it has been given in
已经达成协议
a way that both sides have expected
双方都期望的一种方式
right that that process is long-running
那个过程是长期的
involves multiple steps potentially over
可能涉及多个步骤
multiple days or weeks or months and if
数天或数周或数月，如果
they're and maybe maybe these processes
他们也许是这些过程
are actually time bounded right they can
他们实际上是有时间限制的
take longer than an hour but they could
需要一个多小时，但他们可以
and should not take rather less than or
并且不应少于或少于
they shouldn't take more than let's say
他们不应该多说
a couple days right that's another thing
几天，那是另一回事
you might have time bounds on this so
您可能对此有时间限制
modeling that asynchronicity the fact
对事实进行异步建模
that there's human beings involved that
有人类参与其中
are waiting modeling the sort of
正在等待建模
movement of work from one node to
工作从一个节点移动到
another in the system and from one
系统中的另一个
person to another person in the system
一个人给系统中的另一个人
these kinds of long-running processes
这些长期运行的过程
are business processes they map very
是他们非常映射的业务流程
naturally to the way the business
很自然地成为业务方式
analyst in your organization thinks
您组织中的分析师认为
about what you are doing and that's by
关于你在做什么，那是通过
by design okay
通过设计好吗
workflow is all about describing the
工作流程就是关于描述
work in an organization and workflow
在组织和工作流程中工作
solutions like global aim to make it
像全球目标这样的解决方案
possible to describe these workflow
可能描述这些工作流程
processes these processes that are
处理这些过程
business critical in a way that business
对业务至关重要的方式
analyst can appreciate and so as often
分析师可以欣赏，因此经常
is not there's a modeling component to
没有建模组件
this and it makes it aims to make that
这，它旨在使
that that model
那型号
executable right in there or at least
至少在其中可执行文件
something that could be with a little
可能有一点点的东西
bit of finesse turned into an executable
一点技巧变成了可执行文件
specification so this is what we mean
规范，这就是我们的意思
when we talk about workflow systems all
当我们谈论工作流系统时
right another common example is just a
对，另一个常见的例子就是
very simple you know something you might
很简单，你知道一些你可能会
have you know done a million times I
你知道我做了一百万次吗
want to sign up for a website I go to a
想注册一个网站，我去
website I fill out a form I put my email
网站，我填写表格，我输入电子邮件
they want to validate my email they send
他们想验证我发送的电子邮件
me an email to click it with a with a
给我发送电子邮件，以单击
link I click on the link and that resets
链接我点击链接，然后重置
you know that when I click on the link
你知道当我点击链接
that triggers an endpoint in the website
触发网站中的端点
that then says okay good your what your
然后说好吧，你的好吗
emails been confirmed your consecrated
电子邮件已确认您已奉献
and then you're done right even that
然后你就完成了
simple thing has a few steps involving
简单的事情涉及几个步骤
an automatic system sending out email
自动发送电子邮件的系统
and a human being interacting at some
和一个人在某些地方互动
point asynchronously the time
异步指出时间
potentially in one second one nanosecond
可能在一秒一纳秒内
or one year right you know in this case
或一年的权利，在这种情况下
it might not be critical that the person
那个人可能并不重要
click on a link now they might click on
点击链接，现在他们可能会点击
it in a year and then so what you know
一年后，然后你知道什么
the account should be valid then you
该帐户应该有效，然后您
know Amazon wants a customer whenever
知道亚马逊随时都希望有客户
can get it it doesn't care if he signed
可以得到它，不管他是否签字
up now and forgot to click on the
现在起来，忘了点击
confirmation link until next year
确认链接，直到明年
they're happy to have you next year too
他们也很高兴明年也有你
right as long as all the sort of the
只要各种
killers are the same and invalid right
杀手是一样的，无效的权利
your credit card and billing address but
您的信用卡和帐单地址，但是
I'm sure they'll figure that out after
我相信他们会在以后找到答案的
you've clicked on the link right so so
您已经单击了正确的链接，因此
that these kinds of things these kind of
这些东西这类的
this dimension these dimensions of the
这个尺寸的这些尺寸
process are things that you would model
过程就是您要建模的东西
in a process engine a workflow engine
在流程引擎中，工作流程引擎
and there's been a lot of different
而且有很多不同
attempts at addressing this there's been
试图解决这个问题
a lot of a different attempts to sort of
很多不同的尝试
support these use cases there was a
支持这些用例有一个
particularly misguided one called people
特别是被误导的人
BPEL years ago and people was a way to
BPEL几年前，人们是
describe orchestration it does serve the
描述编排确实为
orchestration and it awkwardly ignored
编排，笨拙地忽略了
completely the role of human actors in
完全将人类演员的角色
the system there's no task list there's
系统中没有任务列表
no mechanism by which tie to to create
没有建立联系的机制
work and then assign that work to people
工作，然后将工作分配给人们
in the in in the inner system and so
在内部系统中
this is a bit unfortunate because really
这有点不幸，因为真的
you know we don't need help
你知道我们不需要帮助
connecting automatic I mean except for
自动连接，我的意思是除了
the audit of audibility that's nice but
可听性的审核很好，但是
we didn't really need help
我们真的不需要帮助
I think connecting services
我认为连接服务
services we already knew how to do that
我们已经知道如何做到的服务
right well what really went needed to be
好吧，真正需要去做的是
done is to model or to design the the
做的是建模或设计
sort of movement of work in an
工作中的某种运动
organization with people involved and so
组织人员参与等等
this got to be such a big problem that
这一定是一个大问题
eventually they created and I do laugh
最终他们创造了，我笑了
even just thinking about it cuz it's so
甚至只是在想它，因为它是如此
absurd they could people for people BPL
他们可以为人而荒谬的BPL
for people and this was an attempt to
对于人们来说，这是一种尝试
sort of address that glaring limitation
那种明显限制的地址
right it's sort of like imagine building
对，有点像想象中的建筑
a you know imagine trying to build
一个你知道想象的尝试建立
hibernate but having no database access
休眠但没有数据库访问权限
right there's no there's no ability to
对，没有能力
write objects your database you can't
向数据库中写入对象
really say it's a nor and without that
真的说这是一个没有，没有那个
right that that's sort of the point
对，这就是重点
right in the same way I feel like people
就像我感觉像人一样
missed out on it's one thing you know I
错过了这是一件事，你知道我
you know that you've heard the the often
你知道你经常听到
bantered you had one job this is that
戏you你有一份工作是
this is that exact scenario so so enter
这是确切的情况，所以输入
people for people that's certainly one
人对于人来说肯定是一个
option there have been a number of other
选择还有其他一些
sort of proprietary solutions or and
某种专有解决方案或
when I say proprietary you know there's
当我说专有时，你知道
aqua logic BPM and you know a bunch of
Aqua Aqua BPM，您知道很多
other all these different infrastructure
其他所有这些不同的基础架构
vendors middleware vendors uh have their
供应商中间件供应商
own workflow solution my journey began
自己的工作流程解决方案，我的旅程开始了
with workflow fifteen years ago and I
与十五年前的工作流程
found myself actually 11 years ago
11年前发现自己
working in a company building my own
在自己的公司里工作
right building my own highly skilled
正确建立自己的高技能
work plungin because I want to build to
努力工作，因为我想建立
support orchestrating work across a
支持跨组织的编排工作
number of nodes and integrating people
节点数和整合人员
into a long-running process involved in
进入一个长期运行的过程
managing the production and and sort of
管理生产和种类
movement of video assets in a system so
视频资产在系统中的移动
we wanted to build we wanted to be able
我们想要建立我们想要的能力
to talk about work across multiple nodes
谈论跨多个节点的工作
and this is actually one of those things
这实际上是其中之一
that's more salient than ever I think in
这比我想像的要重要得多
the in the world of micro services and
微服务世界和
so on right you've got these otherwise
所以就对了，否则
singly focused autonomous sort of micro
单焦点自主微
services that might be enlisted in in a
可能在某项服务中征募的服务
larger enclosing process or process
较大的封闭过程或过程
right so so this use case feels very
对，所以这个用例感觉非常
familiar to me
我熟悉
there were proprietary solutions and I
有专有的解决方案，我
use the word proprietary in this case
在这种情况下，请使用专有一词
now to mean just
现在只是
unique not based on a standard one of
不基于标准之一
those was jbpm which is an open source
那些是开源的jbpm
app at I don't think it was Apache 2
我认为不是Apache 2的应用程序
license but it was an open open source
许可证，但它是一个开放源代码
were plunging from from originally from
从最初的暴跌
a separate project started by a guy
一个人开始的一个单独的项目
named Tom Baines buy-ins
名为汤姆·贝恩斯的买进
and that parties eventually landed at
各方最终降落在
Red Hat JB at the JBoss group at Red Hat
Red Hat JBoss小组的Red Hat JB
which I suppose is now the JBoss coop at
我想现在是JBoss合作社
at IBM and gbpm was pretty dope and I
在IBM和gbpm上我很漂亮
liked it and eventually that gotta you
喜欢它，最终那得你
know for reasons just leave it there J
因为某种原因知道就把它留在那里
bus jbpm for finally sprouted some ok
巴士jbpm终于发芽了一些确定
spring support but that was the end of
Spring 的支持，但这就是结束
the life of that particular tree of JPM
JPM的那棵特定树的生命
eventually the team working on that
最终团队致力于
eventually went off to to alfresco and
最终去露天
they created an a new workflow engine
他们创建了一个新的工作流引擎
that was Tom by aunt and your embarras
那是汤姆姨妈和你的尴尬
my my friend your um they went off to
我的朋友，你嗯，他们去了
alfresco and they created a well
露天，他们创造了一口井
actually they're both my friends but
其实他们都是我的朋友，但是
Urim is the one I with whom I've had the
乌里姆（Urim）是我与之共处的那个人
privilege of sort of more more often
更多的特权
interacting these days they weren't
这些天，他们不是互动
often created something called activity
通常创造一种叫做活动的东西
a CT IV iti and alfresco San Apache 2
CT IV iti和露天San Apache 2
license open-source workflow engine and
许可开源工作流引擎和
in 2010 dr. sire Dave sire on the spring
在2010年父亲戴夫（Dave）父亲在 Spring
team he reached out to them I
他向他们伸出援手的团队
contemporaneously not knowing about
同时不知道
Dave's interactions reached out to them
Dave的互动吸引了他们
and and eventually you know dr. sire
最终你认识了父亲
ended up contributing the the skeletal
最终贡献了骨骼
bare bones sort of integration for
裸露的骨肉
spring I ended up contributing spring
Spring 我结束了 Spring 的贡献
integration the framework spur
整合框架
innovation support for activity and and
对活动和活动的创新支持
and working on dr. sires bare bones sort
和博士。父亲裸露的骨头排序
of spring intubation and then a few
Spring 插管，然后几次
years later back in 2014 or 15 one of
几年后回到2014年或15年之一
those I went back and I added the spring
我回去的那些，我加了 Spring
boot support for activity and you know
启动活动支持，您知道
at that point it got to the it went from
在那个时候它到达了
being this thing that was very hard to
这个东西很难
to get up and running in Java code and
以Java代码启动并运行
that by the way is I think
顺便说一句，我认为
key thing here activity as with jbpm
与jbpm一样的关键活动
were designed to be used by developers
设计供开发人员使用
these are api's that you can use as a
这些是api，您可以将其用作
library there are servers that you can
库中有一些服务器可以
buy there's actually infrastructure that
购买实际上有基础设施
you can buy and deploy but the really
您可以购买和部署，但实际上
sweet spot for me is that I can take
对我来说，最棒的地方是我可以接受
this library take the jars just add it
这个图书馆把罐子加进去
to my class pack
到我的课包里
let's spring boot auto-configure a
让我们春季引导自动配置一个
process engine deploy a few process
流程引擎部署一些流程
definitions and then I'm off to the
定义，然后我开始
races and I can integrate it into it I
比赛，我可以将其整合到其中
can hang off this workflows solution off
可以取消此工作流程解决方案
the side of my of my my business
我本人的一面
application right no problems and I can
申请权没问题，我可以
integrate with all the things that
与所有事物融合
spring knows about including spring
Spring 知道包括 Spring
innovation including spring data I can
我可以进行包括Spring 数据在内的创新
take advantage of transaction management
利用交易管理
and I can do messaging I can do all
我可以做消息我可以做所有
these kinds of things that would have
这些事情本来会
been much more difficult to do in
在这里很难做
solutions from 10 15 years ago wherein
10 15年前的解决方案，其中
you had very little control over the
您几乎无法控制
runtime behavior of the end of the of
结束时的运行时行为
the specification so so activity was
规格，所以活动是
very interesting library and I was
非常有趣的图书馆，我当时
particularly enamored of it one thing
特别迷恋一件事
that was novel about it was that it
那是新奇的
supported bpmn okay so whereas jbpm
支持bpmn好的，所以jbpm
supported its own JP DL a workflow
支持自己的JP DL工作流程
format that only gave me Gais BBM
只给我Gais BBM的格式
supported BPMN was a new specification
受支持的BPMN是新规范
at the time and srebp men too was a new
在那个时候，男人也很新
specification at the time that delivered
交货时的规格
on something that was sort of the holy
在某种神圣的东西上
grail of of real unguent people the one
真正的无耻人的圣杯
I just finished describing was a it was
我刚刚描述的是
a way to describe the execution of a
一种描述执行的方式
workflow but it had a limited thick
工作流程，但是它的厚度有限
limit set limited a set of things that
极限集
you could actually do with it
你实际上可以做到这一点
contemporaneous with that was bpmn which
与之同时存在的是bpmn
is the Business Process Model and
是业务流程模型，
notation which as the name implies
顾名思义的符号
focused more on the iconography the the
更着重于
modeling of processes that is to say the
过程建模，也就是说
picture the the diagram that you would
画出你想要的图表
draw to model a business process it
绘制业务流程模型
didn't really describe an executive
并没有真正形容高管
component and it didn't exactly specify
组件，但未完全指定
how one of these diagrams how one of
这些图之一如何
these visual pictures of a workflow
这些工作流程的视觉图片
diagram would map to runtime semantics
图将映射到运行时语义
and that was a bit of a bit of a bummer
那真是太可惜了
so a lot of different infrastructure and
所以很多不同的基础设施
middleware vendors provided products
中间件厂商提供的产品
that bridged these worlds they provided
桥接了他们提供的这些世界
products that would let you describe a
可以让您描述
workflow using visual tools that you
使用可视工具的工作流程
could drag and draw and and then that
可以拖动并绘制，然后
would be mapped to people or to the
将被映射到人或
subset it was a subset of it would be
它是它的一个子集
mapped to people and that was
映射到人，那是
problematic because it was hard to
有问题的，因为很难
roundtrip and because you could express
往返，因为你可以表达
things in BPMN they could not run in
BPMN中无法运行的东西
people because it was so limited and so
人们，因为它是如此有限，所以
BPA meant to fixed that it actually
BPA旨在修正它实际上
provides it actually specified the
提供它实际指定的
runtime semantics for B PMON process and
B PMON进程的运行时语义和
that I think is where things really got
我认为这才是真正的去处
interesting so activity supports this it
有趣，所以活动支持它
had spring boot support it supports
有 spring boot 支持它支持
integration with all the sort of common
与各种常见的集成
infrastructure with which you may be
您可能所处的基础设施
familiar and I would say that's a very
熟悉，我会说这是非常
good start well things get you know
好的开始，一切都会让你知道
things move fast in this industry so but
这个行业发展很快，所以
two years ago stroke of 2016 the folks
两年前2016年的中风
on the activity team really they wanted
在活动团队中，他们确实想要
to expand considerably the focus of
大大扩展
workflow they wanted to go beyond just
他们想要超越的工作流程
basically flow so they created a new
基本上是流动的，所以他们创造了一个新的
company and a new project called
公司和一个新项目，名为
flowable and if you've used activity
流动性，如果您使用过活动
then flowable which is an also which is
然后流动，这也是
also an apache 2 licensed spring-based
也是基于Apache 2的Spring许可
now it's now actually end-to-end
现在实际上是端到端
integrate with spring it's an apache
与Spring集成，这是一个Apache
license workflow engine just as before
像以前一样许可工作流引擎
and it works a lot in the very same way
它以相同的方式起作用
and has good spring boot starters and
并具有良好的 spring boot 启动器和
integration with all the common hooks it
与所有常见的钩子集成
with with what you might be a customed
与您可能是自定义的
flowable is a new company it's a new
flowable是一家新公司，这是一家新公司
product and a project and it goes well
产品和项目，进展顺利
beyond that it actually supports case
除此之外，它实际上支持案例
management it supports decision trees
支持决策树的管理
and supports form in you know building
并支持您知道的建筑形式
dynamic forms based on processes so it
基于流程的动态表单
has a whole suite of things that you
有一整套的东西，你
will find enterprises want right it's
会发现企业想要正确的
great for people don't want to move
非常适合不想移动的人
documents around this is a Global's one
周围的文件是全球的
of those things where if you're in a
这些东西中，如果你在
bank if you're an insurance company if
银行，如果您是保险公司，如果
you're in a government then global is
你在政府，那么全球
your one-stop-shop for
您的一站式服务
building audit audit compliant compliant
符合建筑审核审核
processes it's absolutely amazing it's
处理过程绝对是惊人的
also BPMN too right so it goes well
BPMN也太正确了，所以进展顺利
beyond just process management today
不仅限于今天的流程管理
we're gonna focus on process management
我们将专注于流程管理
the ability to describe a process that
描述过程的能力
has some steps and then to to be able to
有一些步骤，然后才能
see what that looks like
看看看起来像什么
that's all we're just gonna just gonna
这就是我们所要做的
kind of build a simple process with with
用...构建一个简单的过程
spring boot mmm and we're gonna ignore
spring boot mmm，我们将忽略
for now the these other capabilities
现在，这些其他功能
like I say I think we might end up doing
就像我说的，我认为我们可能最终会做
other videos if not now maybe tomorrow
其他视频，如果不是现在，也许明天
right baby maybe next year next week who
合适的孩子，也许明年下周谁
knows but uh this is start with simple
知道，但这是从简单开始
okay so I'm gonna build a a simple demo
好的，我要构建一个简单的演示
here on the spring initializer and I'm
在Spring初始值设定项上，我是
gonna use the web support I'll use a
要使用网络支持，我将使用
Lombok I'll use h2 I'll use a JDBC
龙目岛我将使用h2我将使用JDBC
support here as well I'm gonna use the
在这里也支持，我将使用
actuator and maybe I'll use JPA I'm not
执行器，也许我会用JPA，我不是
sure if I used a paean we might not have
确定如果我用过潘恩，我们可能没有
time but you know it'll be nice to have
时间，但是你知道拥有它会很好
that I might use security let's go ahead
我可能会使用安全性，让我们继续
and add that and there is no flowable
并补充说，没有流动
checkbox but that's okay because they
复选框，但这没关系，因为他们
already have a very simple dependence
已经有一个非常简单的依赖
you can add and those that dependency
您可以添加和那些依赖
that started a dependency reacts to the
开始依赖的人对
presence of these other types so it'll
这些其他类型的存在，所以它会
auto configure the right thing is based
自动配置正确的事物是基于
on what we're trying to do here so let's
关于我们在这里试图做的事情，所以让我们
go ahead and start that up
继续并开始
already it's on its way and here we go
已经在路上了，我们去
all I'm gonna do is I'm going to add the
我要做的就是添加
dependencies that we need to our
我们需要的依赖
application let me make this font a
应用程序让我将此字体
little bit larger here between my
我之间的距离稍大
friends all right and I have the
好的朋友，我有
dependencies that I'm gonna use here off
我将在这里使用的依赖
to the side go back to the build now a
一边回到现在的构建
word so I could add global spring boots
一句话，所以我可以添加全局 spring boot
started basic and that would bring in
从基本开始，那会带来
everything it would bring in the case
它会带来的一切
management support I do it it would
管理支持我做到了
bring in the workflow engine the process
将工作流程引擎引入流程
engine it would bring in it would bring
它将带来的引擎
in you know everything it would bring in
在你知道它将带来的一切
the document to bring the decision trees
带来决策树的文档
and bring in forums and bringing
并带来论坛和带来
everything but I don't want all that I
一切，但我不想我所有
just want the process engine for now
现在只想要流程引擎
because as I say there's an infinite
因为正如我所说，存在无限
number of things that we could do so
我们可以做到的事情数量
let's just get the flow will end engine
让我们来看看流程将结束引擎
that let's use I guess six step 4.0
让我们使用，我猜六步4.0
property 6.4 times zero
属性6.4零
all right there we are
好吧，我们在那里
so that's the that's thief the flowable
那就是那个小偷
engine uh and you know that's that's
引擎呃，你知道那就是
most of it we're already halfway there
大部分我们已经中途了
we've already got like I can add more I
我们已经可以添加更多我
can add a REST API so you can actually
可以添加REST API，因此您实际上可以
if you just want to build a flowable
如果你只是想建立一个流动的
server basically the formal server is is
服务器基本上正式服务器是
a REST API that you can use to launch
可以用来启动的REST API
query interrogate update the state of
查询询问更新状态
workflow processes okay so you can do
工作流程很好，所以您可以
interesting things there what I want to
有趣的事情在那里我想要
do is I want to actually build a process
我要做的是实际建立流程
and so by date by convention if you
因此，按照惯例，如果您按日期
build a process and you put it in the
建立一个流程，然后将其放入
source main resources processes
源主要资源过程
directory like so it'll automatically
像这样的目录，它将自动
install that process in the process
在过程中安装该过程
engine what process engine you say well
你说什么流程引擎好
the one that's gonna be auto configured
将被自动配置的
for us by virtue of the fact that we've
因为我们已经
got spring boot starter process where is
spring boot 启动器过程在哪里
it going to auto configure its gonna
它会自动配置它
talk to a to sequel database it's gonna
与续集数据库交谈
store the tables that describe these
存储描述这些的表
processes and their histories in that
过程及其历史
database for us and if we have
数据库，如果我们有
configured as sequel database using
使用以下内容配置为续集数据库
regular spring boot is ins like
常规的 spring boot 就像
springing up data source that URL it
涌现该URL的数据源
would instead defer to that right so we
而是会顺从那个权利，所以我们
can actually see there's global dot
可以实际看到全局点
sequel dot hey go you can see there's
续集点嘿，你可以看到
global configuration files here fer for
全局配置文件在这里供
the schema that you might want to use
您可能要使用的架构
right so close phrase right everything's
对这么近的短语对吧
here so that would just get installed
在这里，这样就可以安装了
automatically so you know really you're
自动知道你是真的
already done you've already got the hard
已经做完了
part done this used to be a much more
做到这一点过去要多得多
difficult thing to do with David VM it
与David VM一起做困难的事
used to be more difficult in the early
以前在早期比较困难
days with activity the fact that we've
活动的天，我们已经
already got a working flow workflow
已经有了工作流程的工作流程
engine at this point is really nice we
此时的引擎真的很棒，我们
don't actually have the REST API like I
实际上没有像我这样的REST API
said I've chosen only to have the
说我只选择拥有
process engine not the REST API and not
流程引擎不是REST API，不是
that hibernate and JPA configuration
休眠和JPA配置
nothing else so I'm just gonna go ahead
没有别的，所以我要继续
and comment out some of the stuff that
并注释掉一些
we don't need just yet okay and it's we
我们不需要还好，就是我们
could let's take a look at what this
让我们看看这是什么
brings in
带进
so click on this and we've got the JBC
所以点击这个，我们有JBC
support test support the auto
支持测试支持自动
configuration the engine testing there
在此处配置引擎测试
you go
你走
that brings in a bunch of modules so you
带来了很多模块，所以你
can see these other modules there's
可以看到这些其他模块
integration there's the actuate of
整合有一个驱动力
support there's the process in the
支持其中的过程
process REST API the apps the REST API
处理REST API的应用程序REST API
the you know the rate regular essay yeah
你知道利率定期论文是的
I mean just all this cool stuff so all
我的意思是所有这些很酷的东西
we care about right now is just a
我们现在关心的只是一个
flowable process engine so I will I will
可流动的流程引擎，所以我会
instead revert to our change okay there
而是恢复到我们的更改好吗
we are global spring boot starter
我们是全球性的 spring boot 者
process very good so now let's create a
过程非常好，现在让我们创建一个
process I've got a process that's a very
我有一个非常
simple process BPMN is you know it's not
简单的过程BPMN是您知道的吗
the easiest thing to write by hand um it
最简单的手写方法
could be done but flowable very
可以做到，但很容易流动
conveniently comes with a nice little
方便地带有一个漂亮的小东西
modeler here and so you don't need to
在这里建模，所以您不需要
write it by hand and I certainly
用手写，我当然
wouldn't for anything more sophisticated
不需要更复杂的东西
more complicated you can see it's very
比较复杂，您可以看到它非常
easy to get started here you just
容易上手这里
download flobbles executable spring
下载flobbles可执行文件spring
boudoirs there dot wores you can deploy
您可以部署的点点穿的闺房
them to a classic a servlet environment
他们到经典的servlet环境
container or just do java - jar you know
容器还是只做Java-Jar就知道了
global - IDM var and then flowable
全局-IDM var，然后可流动
modeler var and you'll you'll have I've
建模者var，您将拥有我拥有的
got - I've got those two wires running
-我的那两条电线都在运转
in the background and with that I have
在后台，我有
the API and I have this visual modeler
API，我有这个视觉建模者
and I can actually model decision tables
我实际上可以为决策表建模
I can model forms cases a case is these
我可以为表格案例建模
cases are using C mmm and right and you
案例使用C mmm，对，您
know this in a case you it's a way of
知道这一点，这是你的一种方式
it's not just a process you can actually
这不只是一个过程，您实际上可以
you in a case you're actually telling
如果您实际上是在告诉您
the engine I have these things that need
引擎我有这些需要的东西
to be tracked in the real world and they
在现实世界中被追踪，他们
are events and I want those events to
是事件，我希望这些事件能够
result in actions if and one of those
导致以下情况之一
actions could be the launching of a new
行动可能是发起新的
process but it's more than just the
过程，但不仅仅是
process itself it's actually more of a
处理本身实际上更多的是
it's more of a stateful thing and it
这更多的是有状态的事情，
keeps the Kalu that listens for things
保持侦听事情的Kalu
in the outside world this is actually
在外面，这实际上是
there's a lot more to it that's why
这还有很多，这就是为什么
we're gonna cook cover this perhaps in
我们要煮这也许在
another video but for now let's focus on
另一个视频，但现在让我们关注
processes and what I'm gonna do is I'm
流程，我要做的就是
going to import an existing process that
将要导入的现有流程
I've already got here in the desktop
我已经在桌面上了
this is the famous single task process
这是著名的单任务流程
right so what do we got here we've got a
对，所以我们到这里来了
task a user task actually this is a user
任务用户用户任务实际上是用户
task you can see that we have a this is
任务，您可以看到我们有一个
a full-featured visually visual modeling
全功能的视觉视觉建模
tool so we have you know structural
工具，让我们知道您的结构
components we have gateways we have
我们拥有的组件我们拥有的网关
events we have swim lanes we have
我们有活动的泳道
artifacts I don't now let's talk about
我现在不谈论的文物
this let's think about this here start
让我们从这里开始思考
events all processes start somewhere so
事件所有进程都从某个地方开始
you have to have the start event there's
你必须要有开始事件
different types of starts up some based
不同类型的启动基于
on an event from outside some based on a
在某个外部事件的基础上
timer
计时器
you know etc like you know I want to do
你知道我想做的事
it every I'm gonna start off new process
我将要开始新的过程
every 5 seconds whatever you have
每5秒，无论您拥有什么
activities and then you have let's see
活动，然后让我们看看
you have you have activities these refer
你有活动，这些是指
mostly to tasks so a very common the
主要是任务，所以很常见
ones we're gonna use today are user
我们今天要使用的是用户
tasks and service tasks a user task is a
任务和服务任务用户任务是
task that's assigned to somebody so you
分配给某人的任务，所以您
can see it's got their the human
可以看到有他们的人
silhouette right they come in the head
他们进入脑袋的正确剪影
silhouette there and a service task is
剪影在那里，服务任务是
an automatic sort of thing it's in its
它是一种自动的东西
part of the graph and this is actually
图的一部分，这实际上是
what that is this is a process graph
这是一个流程图
right so you're gonna see that the
对，所以您会看到
workflow will start on the left it'll
工作流程将从左侧开始
arrive at the human task at which point
在这一点上完成人工任务
there's gonna be a list that I can query
会有一个我可以查询的清单
right I can actually programmatically
对，我实际上可以以编程方式
ask the engine I can say hey how many
问引擎我可以说嘿
you know what tasks for these processes
你知道这些过程的任务
are outstanding and I can say okay well
非常出色，我可以说很好
what about tasks for this process for
那这个过程的任务呢
this particular user right so when I
这个特定的用户权利，所以当我
launch this process I can give it
启动这个过程我可以给它
parameters I can say okay this is the
我可以说参数是
process for customer ID you know 1 2 3
您知道的客户ID的流程1 2 3
and I can then say ok process engine I
然后我可以说好的流程引擎
show me how many processes are stuck or
告诉我有多少过程卡住了
waiting at this my tasks tasks for the
在此等待我的任务
user you know that I'm I'm logged in as
用户，您知道我是以以下身份登录
for example right so I can actually I
例如对，这样我就可以
can I can say give me all the work to do
我能说给我所有的工作吗
for this user in this particular process
在此特定过程中为此用户
and then I can complete it or I can just
然后我可以完成它或者我可以
ignore it
忽略它
but while the workflow engine has paused
但是当工作流引擎暂停时
here it saves the state into the system
这里将状态保存到系统中
and it's gone no it doesn't move forward
它走了，不，它不会前进
until somebody comes along and says hey
直到有人过来说嘿
I'm gonna clean this task and I'm gonna
我要清理这个任务，我要
complete it right I'm gonna say it's
正确完成我要说的是
done you know who did it it's J long it
你知道是谁做的吗
doesn't have to be I don't have to
不必是我不必
specify user but you can the point is
指定用户，但您可以指出的是
that this is an outstanding task that
这是一项艰巨的任务
can be assigned to somebody you can
可以分配给可以的人
actually have this show up in somebody's
实际出现在某人的
sort of a work list you can dry it you
你可以把工作清单弄干
can draw a screen that shows all the
可以绘制一个屏幕，显示所有
work that has to be done and then they
必须完成的工作，然后他们
can do whatever it is that they have to
可以做他们必须要做的一切
do they can review a form they can you
他们可以审查表格吗？
know upload some information they can
知道可以上传一些信息
call so whatever they want to do and
打电话给他们想做什么
they can say ok I'm done or the system
他们可以说确定，我已经完成或系统
can by virtue of their inputs say ok the
可以根据他们的输入说好
task is done and then it can officially
任务完成，然后可以正式
and programmatically call complete at
然后以编程方式在
which point the flow proceeds to the
流程前进到哪一点
next node in the graph and this is just
图中的下一个节点，这仅仅是
a service task this is just a basic
服务任务，这仅仅是一个基本的
escape hatch it's just our ability it's
逃脱孵化只是我们的能力
this thing that we use to call some
我们用来称呼这个东西的东西
other thing to call some other code and
调用其他代码的另一件事
you know what that is is kind of up to
你知道那是什么
you it can be a class or it can be a
你可以是一个班级也可以是一个
spring expression language expression
Spring Expression Language 表达
which of course can because of the tight
当然可以因为紧缩
integration with spring dereference any
与spring解除引用集成
spring bean in your application context
您的应用程序上下文中的spring bean
so you can actually call methods on
因此您实际上可以在
other beans and so on and then once
其他beans等等，然后一次
that's done it goes to the end state and
完成后，它将进入最终状态，
so I can actually this process might
所以我实际上可以
take who knows right I mean imagine this
拿谁知道是对的，我的意思是想象这个
is a sign up for
报名参加
imagine somebody enters a you know an
想象有人进入一个你知道的
email and and you know you've got an
电子邮件，并且您知道您有一个
email and the user ID you've created in
电子邮件和您在其中创建的用户ID
the database and then you kick off this
数据库，然后您开始
process and the process is the process
过程，过程就是过程
of filling out or enriching the rest of
填充或丰富其余部分
the data well you know you you might
数据，您知道您可能会
launch the process and it may never
启动该过程，它可能永远不会
finish it may never get finished but um
完成它可能永远不会完成，但嗯
you launch the process and you can say
您启动该过程，您可以说
we're waiting on the user to fill out
我们正在等待用户填写
the rest of this form when they do that
他们这样做时的其余形式
we'll complete it once they've filled
他们填满后我们会完成
out the rest of this form well then send
拿出这份表格的其余部分，然后发送
them an email over here in the service
向他们发送服务中的电子邮件
task once that's done we're done the
任务一旦完成，我们就完成了
user has been enrolled right this is a
用户已被注册，这是一个
very simple example now you can do some
非常简单的示例，现在您可以做一些
really interesting things here you can
这里真的很有趣
say oh well the result of this form was
说哦，好吧，这张表格的结果是
that we have a new record in the
我们有一个新的记录
database which created a new ID and
创建新ID的数据库，以及
we've now attached that ID to this
我们现在已经将该ID附加到此
process as a process variable right so
作为过程变量的过程，所以
now things downstream like the service
现在下游的东西就像服务
tasks can say oh I can see the process
任务可以说哦，我可以看到流程
variable it's just a string it's just an
变量，它只是一个字符串，它只是一个
ID a number in a boolean these
用布尔值ID标识这些数字
primitives can travel in the graph in
图元可以在图中移动
the in the process graph and you can do
在流程图中，您可以执行
things you can say oh well maybe that
你可以说的话哦，也许那个
you know I can use a process variable
你知道我可以使用过程变量
set either the beginning of the process
设置过程的开始
or at some component after it started I
或它开始后的某个部分
can use those process variables
可以使用那些过程变量
downstream I can say oh well based on
下游我可以说很好
this condition that I'm evaluating by by
我正在评估的这种情况
looking at the variable or by passing
看变量或通过
the variable to a condition to a method
方法条件的变量
that does some sort of evaluation based
基于某种评估
on that result I'm gonna either go here
基于这个结果，我要么去这里
or I'm gonna go there so I might say oh
否则我要去那里，所以我可能会说哦
well this input is invalid and I might
这个输入是无效的，我可能
have a sort of a recursive effect where
具有某种递归效果
I go back to the first step to collect
我回到第一步来收集
more input you know and I can keep doing
您知道更多的输入，我可以继续做
that infinite ad infinitum and it can
无限的广告无限
take years if it needs to it can take a
需要几年的时间
minute you know whatever and then
分钟，你什么都知道，然后
finally once the data once this thing
终于一次数据一次这个东西
says all the data is valid it proceeds
说所有数据都是有效的
back to this it sends the email so you
返回到此它发送电子邮件，所以你
can do that you can do gateways where
可以做到，您可以在哪里做网关
you might have this you know this this
你可能有这个，你知道这个
task where you collect some collect some
您收集一些的任务收集一些
information once that's finished you
完成信息后，您
know you might say oh I'm gonna set some
知道你可能会说哦，我要设置一些
email here and I'm gonna kick off
在这里发送电子邮件，我将开始
another flow another
另一个流另一个
of him from of processing another part
他从处理另一部分
of the graph another branch in the graph
图的另一个分支
and over here we're gonna you know send
在这里，我们将要发送
them the whatever the the fulfilment you
他们无论你实现什么
know we're gonna start the fulfillment
知道我们要开始实现
process or we're gonna send them cards
流程，否则我们将向他们发送卡片
you know membership cards whatever right
你知道会员卡什么权利
you might you might do two different
你可能会做两个不同的事情
things at the same time right so in this
事情在同一时间，所以在这个
case you've got a parallel gateway right
如果您有一个并行网关，
you're actually sending you're starting
你实际上是在发送你的开始
up two different flows of execution that
两种不同的执行流程
happen to concurrently and you could go
碰巧同时发生，你可以去
even step further you could say okay
甚至走得更远，您都可以说还可以
well this step over here this branch
好吧，这个分支的这一步
over here is not just one service task
这不仅仅是一项服务任务
it is a whole other process that has to
这是整个其他过程
be started now that we've gotten past
现在开始，我们已经过去了
this I want to I want to kick off a
这个我想我想开始
whole new process so in this case you
整个新过程，所以在这种情况下，您
have that you could launch when it's
有你可以在它启动时
called a sub process right you can
您可以将其称为子流程
actually instead of having just a little
实际上而不是只有一点点
task you could launch in another process
您可以在另一个过程中启动的任务
that in turn has its own steps and
反过来又有自己的步骤，
States and process variables and white
状态和过程变量和白色
steps and all that right and so that
步骤和所有正确的事情，这样
could be some other process that's
可能是其他一些过程
that's designed to you know whatever you
旨在让您知道
can do risk us risk assessment or you
可以冒险冒险或您
could do the fulfillment process maybe
可以完成履行过程
you're maybe this process is for when
你也许这个过程是为了什么时候
somebody orders something on your
有人在你的东西上点菜
ecommerce engine now you need to do
现在您需要做的电子商务引擎
fulfillment you need to do you know
您需要知道的成就
shipping and tracking and credit card
运输和跟踪以及信用卡
verification all that stuff right so you
验证所有正确的内容，以便您
can model very complex things here with
可以在这里建模非常复杂的东西
these primitives and the result is a VPN
这些原语，结果就是VPN
XML document so now that you've kind of
XML文档，这样您就可以
seen what this looks like you can
看到这看起来像你可以
actually choose to save this just hit
实际上选择保存这只命中
save right I'm gonna hit cancel and you
保存权利，我要点击取消，你
can work with it that way or as I will
可以那样或那样使用它
do you can just copy and paste the file
您可以复制并粘贴文件吗
in to your processes directory okay so
进入您的进程目录好吧
there's this and here's my task here's
这就是这里，这是我的任务
my single task process and it's you know
我的单一任务流程，这是你知道的
simple example and this is straight out
简单的例子，这很简单
of the out of the documentation
文档中的
basically so let's look at what this
基本上，让我们看看这是什么
does this says you know what I'm going
这是否表示您知道我要去哪里
to do this is going to be a simple
做到这一点将很简单
process that's a terrible
这个过程很糟糕
okay I don't know what's a better what's
好吧，我不知道有什么更好的
a better process we can say sign up
我们可以说注册更好的流程
process okay very simple sign up a new
过程还可以，非常简单，注册一个新的
user process process yeah go okay and
用户进程进程是好的，并且
start and you can see that when I have a
开始，您可以看到当我有一个
start event this is the thing that
开始事件就是这样
starts the process it's the first node
启动进程，它是第一个节点
in the graph and then I need to connect
在图中，然后我需要连接
this node to this node and I do that
这个节点到这个节点，我做到了
through a sequence flow element so here
通过序列流元素，所以这里
I'm gonna say I'm gonna put the the work
我要说我要把工作
will progress from start to confirm
从头开始确认
email tasks right and this will be
电子邮件任务正确，这将是
confirm email and finally that task when
确认电子邮件，最后确认该任务
that when that task has been pulled down
当那个任务被取消时
and then manually or explicitly marked
然后手动或显式标记
as complete then work will proceed to
完成后，工作将继续进行
the email task
电子邮件任务
okay um send welcome email task okay and
好的，发送欢迎电子邮件任务，好的，
here we're gonna just send a welcome
在这里，我们将只发送欢迎
email and then we're gonna send that
电子邮件，然后我们将发送给
email by calling on a service of being
通过呼叫存在服务来发送电子邮件
in our application context called email
在我们称为电子邮件的应用程序上下文中
service I'm going to call San welcome
服务我要打电话给圣欢迎
email we're gonna send the welcome email
我们将发送欢迎电子邮件的电子邮件
to this customer ID with a site with
该客户ID和网站
this email and those variables these
这封电子邮件以及这些变量
variables are going to be passed in you
变量将传递给您
know we expect a customer ID and email
知道我们需要客户ID和电子邮件
process variable okay so those process
过程变量好，所以那些过程
variables are like parameters to a
变量就像参数
method invocation so we're gonna expect
方法调用，因此我们可以期待
them to be visible for the entire
它们对于整个人都是可见的
lifetime of this process finally that's
这个过程的生命最后就是
gonna result in a a when that email is
当该电子邮件是
sent then this will automatically be
发送，那么这将自动
completed and it'll progress according
完成，它将根据
to this to end
为此结束
which is this so very very simple
这是如此非常非常简单
workflow process nothing particularly
工作流程过程没什么特别的
fancy and you know that's why design we
看中了，这就是我们设计的原因
could in theory type this by hand right
理论上可以用手直接键入
you saw that this isn't that bad we have
您看到我们还不错
a global namespace that's here right
正确的全局命名空间
that's part of the standard you're able
这是您能够使用的标准的一部分
to extend the definition of a workflow
扩展工作流程的定义
of a BPMN workflow by adding these
BPMN工作流通过添加以下内容
namespaces that's fine right and so here
正确的名称空间，所以在这里
we're saying I want to use an expression
我们是说我想使用一个表达式
and here we're saying that the the
在这里，我们说的是
person that is initiating the process is
启动过程的人是
called the initiator and we're gonna
叫做发起者，我们将
store that somewhere and then reference
将其存储在某个地方，然后引用
that here okay so this is saying figure
好的，这就是说图
out who's initiating the process stash
找出谁在启动流程存储
it somewhere as a variable in the
它在某处作为变量
process definition and then here when we
流程定义，然后当我们
say flow bill assignee I want to I'm
说我要的流水单受让人
gonna take don't do you reference that
要不要引用
in this case we don't have an initiator
在这种情况下，我们没有发起者
really we haven't set up identity
真的我们还没有建立身份
management you could though and you
管理虽然你可以和你
could actually set the process trouble
可能会给过程带来麻烦
yourself in which case you wouldn't need
你自己，在这种情况下你不需要
that you could do all sorts of things
你可以做各种各样的事情
but for what we're doing it doesn't
但是对于我们正在做的事情
really matter so let's now integrate
真的很重要，所以让我们现在整合
this this flow into our code okay so I
这会流到我们的代码中，所以我
guess I'm not sure I you know what's the
猜猜我不确定我是否知道那是什么
easiest way to demo this I suppose we
我想我们最简单的演示方法
could just build a demo a a trailer
可以只制作一个演示预告片
spring bean a regular you know process
Spring bean 一个你知道的常规过程
demo okay and we're just gonna manually
演示好吧，我们只是手动
manipulate the API this the process
操作这个过程的API
engine API to to drive the movement of
引擎API驱动运动
this process to show the progression
这个过程显示进度
okay so enroll new user but it's not
好的，所以要注册新用户，但不是
hard to see or to understand that you
很难看到或理解你
know you would you would have these
知道你会拥有这些
different things happen behind for
不同的事情发生在背后
example a REST API or button clicks on a
例如REST API或按钮点击
spring MVC application or a reactive
Spring MVC应用程序或反应式
application or whatever so in order for
应用程序或其他
me to to address this I am going to
我要解决这个问题
inject the process engine now this is
现在注入流程引擎
usually a little heavy-handed if you
通常如果你有点笨拙
don't know where to go you inject the
不知道要去哪里注射
process engine
流程引擎
okay and the process engine is the heart
好的，流程引擎就是心脏
of the API the process engine is a very
API的过程引擎是一个非常
simple sort of structure here it in turn
简单的结构在这里依次
gives you pointers to the other
给你指向另一个
interesting objects in the workflow
工作流程中有趣的对象
engine and so you get access to the
引擎，因此您可以访问
repository services which is pritchett
pritchett的存储库服务
inserting the the different tables
插入不同的表
you've got the runtime service which
你有运行时服务
gives you access to the the the process
使您可以访问该过程
instances so you've got processes and
实例，所以您拥有流程和
then that's the definition of a process
那就是流程的定义
when the process is when you launch an
该过程何时启动
instance of the process that's called a
该过程的实例称为
process instance when you want to get
您想要获得的流程实例
the variables for a particular process
特定过程的变量
instance you can do so as well you do
实例，你也可以做到
all that from the runtime service the
来自运行时服务的所有内容
task service is all about interacting
任务服务就是关于交互
with tasks that have been arrived at you
已经完成的任务
know here for example I'm gonna want to
知道在这里，例如我要
be able to find all the outstanding
能够找到所有优秀的
unfinished confirmed email tasks right I
未完成的已确认电子邮件任务对吧
can do that with a task service identity
可以使用任务服务标识来做到这一点
service concerns how you teach a mobile
服务关系到您如何教手机
about you know users whether it's
关于您了解用户是否
through LDAP or Active Directory or
通过LDAP或Active Directory或
spring security or whatever so you've
Spring Security 保障或其他
got a you know number of different
有一个你知道数量不同
things here you've even got this thing
在这里，你甚至有这个东西
which I which is fairly new I don't
我是新手，我不是
actually know too much about this one
其实对这件事了解太多
but because it wasn't really there until
但是因为直到那时才真正出现
later for activity but this is actually
稍后进行活动，但这实际上是
very interesting what if you want to
非常有趣，如果您想
create new dynamic branches of execution
创建新的执行动态分支
while the while the engine is running
当引擎运转时
well you've got a process in flight so
好吧，你有一个正在运行的过程，所以
keep in mind this process definition
请记住此流程定义
that I just showed you that's a fixed
我刚刚告诉你这是固定的
graph it's a it's a template that
图是一个模板
represents a fixed definition of the
代表
process once it's defined its rigid its
一旦确定了它的刚性
rigid and and it was such that you
僵硬的，这就是你
couldn't really change that dynamically
不能真正改变这种动态
once you had two launched an instance of
一旦您有两个启动实例
the execution you could deploy a new
您可以部署一个新的执行
instance of the process definition right
流程定义权限的实例
you can deploy a new version of this and
您可以部署新版本
flow but behind the scenes does actually
流动但实际上在幕后
version the process definition so you
版本化流程定义，以便您
can have you know three or four existing
你能知道三个或四个吗
processes of version window in flight
飞行中版本窗口的处理
for whatever some definition of of
无论什么定义
in-flight you can do that but um you can
可以在飞行中做到这一点，但可以
launch a new one or deploy new one and
启动一个新的或部署新的
that will be the
那将是
gets used in the new execution so the
在新的执行中使用，因此
process engine that supports that sort
支持这种排序的流程引擎
of that that versioning that's actually
实际上是那个版本
part of the runtime service and that's
运行时服务的一部分，那就是
part of the history service so you've
历史服务的一部分，因此您已经
got other things that do that but this
还有其他事情可以做到这一点，但这
in particular is if I want to
特别是如果我想
dynamically create new branches in the
动态地在
existing process instance that's running
正在运行的现有流程实例
right now so I can do that I can use a
现在，我可以这样做，我可以使用
the process engine but really for our
流程引擎，但实际上对我们而言
purposes we are going to be okay with
目的，我们会没事的
just the runtime service and the task
只是运行时服务和任务
service so runtime service and all of
服务，因此运行时服务和所有
this is possible because they've already
这是可能的，因为他们已经
got references to the write beans
得到了对写bean的引用
because of Springwood Auto configuration
由于Springwood Auto配置
does that for us
为我们做到了
right runtime service test service and
正确的运行时服务测试服务和
check that into the constructor already
将其检查到构造函数中
so we've got a process we've got a demo
所以我们有一个过程，我们有一个演示
and we're gonna launch a what's that
我们将推出一个
what are we gonna do we're going to
我们要做什么
create several methods here that launch
在这里创建几种启动方法
processes and again you can imagine this
流程，再一次您可以想象
being hung off the side of a REST API or
挂在REST API旁边
in response to user you know if
响应用户，您知道是否
somebody's clicked on a login form or
有人点击了登录表单，或者
something so let's say we've got void
所以说我们已经虚无
begin customer enrollment okay and here
可以开始这里的客户注册
we've already created the user but it's
我们已经创建了用户，但是
an empty user it's in the database but
一个空用户，它在数据库中，但是
there's a whole bunch of no fields and
有一大堆没有领域，
by the way that's another thing is that
顺便说一句是
in these long running processes in these
在这些长期运行的过程中
long running tasks these long running
这些长时间运行的任务
business processes one way that we have
业务流程是我们拥有的一种方式
I'm sure you've seen this before one way
我敢肯定，您已经看过一种方法了
that people try and solve these kinds of
人们尝试解决这些问题
problems is they riddle their customer
问题是他们使客户困惑
entities with boolean you know no lor
布尔型的实体，你不知道
not known is it fulfilled is it you know
不知道实现了吗，你知道吗
it has it has the user signed up has you
它是否已注册用户？
know blah blah blah all these kinds of
知道等等所有这些
things that are designed to give you an
旨在为您提供帮助的东西
idea of where in the process the user is
用户在过程中的位置的想法
and you end up having to do these
而你最终不得不做这些
complex if this and that and that and
如果这个和那个以及那个复杂
then that then we are here right if this
那么那我们就在这里，如果这
is done then great and that's
完成，然后很棒，那就是
inefficient because you have to check
效率低下，因为您必须检查
that state and every turn to figure out
那个状态，动不动就知道
where you are on the graph so that
您在图表上的位置，以便
process stay
流程停留
ends up living in the business entities
最终居住在企业实体中
but it really shouldn't be there right
但它真的不应该在那里
we have a customer that's what it should
我们有一个应有的客户
be and it's either valid or it's not
是，它要么有效，要么无效
right but the process state that should
是的，但是应该是过程状态
live in the process definition so here
存在于流程定义中，所以这里
we can use workflow to store an idea of
我们可以使用工作流来存储
where in the graph we are so I'm gonna
在图中我们在哪里，所以我要
create a I'm gonna begin a customer
创建一个我要开始一个客户
enrollment process whenever sort of
报名过程
calls
来电
whenever somebody fills out the form you
每当有人填写您的表格时
know the enter an email and and whatever
知道输入电子邮件，等等
we then go to the database we save it in
然后我们进入数据库，将其保存在
the name base and we say this is a brand
名字基础，我们说这是一个品牌
new entity but it's invalid right we can
新实体，但这是无效的权利，我们可以
have a boolean flag called invalid I
有一个布尔标记，称为无效I
guess or something and we want an email
猜测之类的，我们想要一封电子邮件
right so something email all right so
对，所以有些电子邮件没问题，所以
that's gonna be one thing we want to say
那就是我们想说的一件事
you know and I want to let's say let's
你知道，我想说让我们
just say we've got some sort of string
只是说我们有一些弦乐
that gets returned back to be able to
返回到能够
further correlate okay so we wanted to
进一步关联好吧，所以我们想
be well we want to be able to do that
很好，我们希望能够做到这一点
log that's actually create a logger okay
实际创建记录器的日志
log info what do we want to return well
日志信息我们想返回什么
I guess we don't really need anything do
我想我们真的不需要做任何事情
we right we could just return a boolean
我们对，我们可以返回一个布尔值
what we're gonna do is when we turn the
我们要做的是当我们打开
process instanceid we don't need it this
流程instanceid我们不需要这个
is nice to be able to observe it okay
很高兴能够观察到它
so here's this and when I say this but
所以这是当我说这个时
that and what customer ID or do we want
那和我们想要的客户ID
to have well let's just say we've got a
让我们只说我们有一个
customer ID of one and the email will be
客户ID为1，电子邮件为
email at email comm this is not a real
在电子邮件通讯中发送电子邮件，这不是真实的
email certainly okay so now at this
电子邮件肯定可以，所以现在在这里
point somebody's submitted a form and
指出有人提交了表格，
they've got you know it's maybe it's a
他们知道你可能是
REST API with some JSON data in it maybe
包含一些JSON数据的REST API
it's a form whatever we have a customer
这是一种形式，无论我们有客户如何
ID and an email and we have an object in
ID和电子邮件，我们有一个对象
the database presumably so we're gonna
大概是数据库，所以我们要
figure out what it means to start the
弄清楚开始
process with those process variables in
用这些过程变量处理
it in this method and then finally
用这种方法，最后
finally we're going to want to look up
最后我们要去抬头
the existing tasks to be because by
现有任务是因为
that point it'll have automatically
那一点它会自动
it'll have automatically progressed from
它会自动从
here down to here it's a user test map
这是用户测试图
it isn't there's a task list of
它不是一个任务列表
outstanding confirmed email tasks that
确认的未完成电子邮件任务
are that are part of this process
这是这个过程的一部分吗
finders in this case there's only gonna
在这种情况下，发现者只会
be one and so you could say okay well
成为一个人，所以你可以说很好
find me all the confirm email tasks for
找到我的所有确认电子邮件任务
the customer whose customer ID we've
我们拥有其客户ID的客户
provided so how would that work well we
提供，那么它将如何运作良好，我们
would say complete you know complete
会说完成，你知道完成
confirm email okay string customer ID
确认电子邮件好字符串客户ID
all right so that's this and I suppose
好的，就是这样，我想
we could for ease of work ease of
为了工作的轻松，我们可以
reference let's extract that out to a
参考让我们将其提取到
customer ID variable create that method
客户ID变量创建该方法
okay so there we go there's my
好，所以我们去那里是我的
confirmation okay you're gonna confirm
确认好，你要确认
the email me
给我发电子邮件
okay so there's my confrim you know and
好吧，所以我知道你的自信
this presumably happens asynchronously
这大概是异步发生的
right this could happen there's no
对，这可能发生，没有
reason this has to happen in the same
原因这必须在同一时间发生
thread or even the same application
线程甚至同一应用程序
because behind the scenes it's gonna get
因为在幕后
to a state in the database it's gonna
到数据库中的状态
get to the state and say okay I'm
到州说好吧我
waiting on somebody to explicitly
等待某人明确
complete me so I'm gonna free up all
完成我，所以我要释放所有
threads I'm gonna write my state to the
我将要写入状态的线程
database and I'm gonna disappear if
数据库，如果
somebody wants to wake me up and say
有人想叫我起床
it's been completed in a year that's
它是在一年内完成的
fine but I'm not gonna sit here and
很好，但我不会坐在这里
monopolize resources on the server
垄断服务器上的资源
waiting for that event that'll happen
等待即将发生的事件
later and so we're you know they think
后来，所以我们你知道他们认为
this is an async thing later on now
这是稍后的异步事情
finally finally once we've done that
终于，一旦我们完成了
well oh actually I guess I guess at this
好吧，哦，我猜我猜到了
point we know what we want to do is we
我们知道我们想做的是
want to get all the tasks outstanding
想要完成所有任务
for this customer and then confirm right
为此客户，然后确认正确
so actually we should how should we
所以实际上我们应该如何
model that I guess we could do that in
我想我们可以做到的模型
this confirmed thing so really that's
这个确定的东西真的是
that's all of it and then we want to
仅此而已，然后我们想
confirm that once that's done that the
确认一旦完成，
component that we are charging with
我们要充电的组件
sending the email has has some record of
发送电子邮件有一些记录
it we want to see that it passes through
我们希望看到它通过
that so let's say we're gonna have a
这么说，我们要有一个
bean called email service which will
bean 称为电子邮件服务，这将
support a method that looks like this go
支持看起来像这样的方法
down here at service and public void
在这里服务和公共场合
send string your string email alright so
发送字符串您的字符串电子邮件好吧
there's that and what do we want to do
那就是我们想要做什么
well I just wanna I just want it for my
好吧，我只是想要我想要的
test here my little example I want to
在这里测试我想做的小例子
have a way of recording the fact that
有办法记录事实
somebody has sent has asked for us to
有人发送了要我们
send an email for that person so I guess
给那个人发送电子邮件，所以我猜
what's the easiest way to do this
最简单的方法是什么
I was gonna store list but that doesn't
我本来要存储列表，但是那不
make sense
说得通
oh you could map string Tomic integer
哦，你可以映射字符串Tomic整数
send hash map and current ash map
发送哈希图和当前的灰图
already and all we're gonna do here is
已经，我们要做的就是
it'll say log first of all ok so there's
它会说首先登录好，所以
that and then we're gonna say this dot
那然后我们要说这个点
don't do full API sends dot put if
不做完整的API发送点放置
absent key and email and a new atomic
缺少密钥和电子邮件以及一个新的原子
integer okay and then say send start get
整数好吧，然后说发送开始
email doc increment and get okay so I'm
电子邮件文档增量，可以，所以我
just gonna you know increment a number
只是你会知道增加一个数字
there and then work with it yeah
在那里然后与它一起工作
actually I could just there you go so
其实我可以就在那里
that's that'll be there that'll work no
那就是那里，那将行不通
matter what now I can now poke at that
不管现在我可以戳一下
that state in my code up here just to
我的代码中的状态只是
confirm so I suppose that I probably
确认，所以我想我可能
could have written this in a unit test
本可以在单元测试中写的
but for now let's just uh let's just see
但现在让我们只是...
actually we could do some unit tests
实际上我们可以做一些单元测试
let's do that in unit test that might
让我们在可能会进行的单元测试中做到这一点
even be easier so here
甚至更容易，所以在这里
go to a test okay and we're just gonna
去测试好吧，我们要
use these we're just gonna inject them
使用这些，我们只是要注入它们
in a unit test here already okay and
在这里的单元测试中已经可以了
we're gonna drive the test from we're
我们要从我们那里进行测试
gonna drive the flow of this process
会推动这一过程的流程
from a test just as we did before just
就像我们之前所做的一样
as we were gonna do before but now I
就像我们以前要做的，但现在我
don't have to you know come up with an
不必知道
excuse to write a certain method when I
我借口写某种方法
already got one you know a nice
已经有一个，你知道一个不错的
framework called Gina so I'll use that
框架叫Gina，所以我将使用它
and by the way there's actually full-on
顺便说一句
unit testing supported for floral as
支持花卉单元测试
well but I'm just using a razor spring
好吧，但我只是用剃刀Spring
good here it's a little bit verbose but
很好，这里有点冗长，但是
hey don't get the job done okay so we
嘿，没把工作做好，所以我们
don't need this just want to have a
不需要这个，只是想有一个
little hello
小小的你好
alrighty so okay
好吧，还好
good so here we go let's try this out so
好，所以我们开始尝试
I'm gonna say this will give us an ID
我要说这会给我们一个ID
process instance ID great cert not no
流程实例ID大证书不是
process instance ID process instance
流程实例ID流程实例
should not be null great okay
不应该为null很好
all messages last okay
所有消息最后都可以
and finally I guess we have to actually
最后我想我们必须
implement that so let's do that we've
实施，让我们做到这一点
got the task service so what does that
得到了任务服务，那是什么
look like well we're gonna use the run
看起来很好，我们要使用跑步
time service we're gonna say this run
时间服务，我们要说这个
time service start the process instance
时间服务启动流程实例
I'm gonna start it by the key well that
我要从关键开始
the key is in the XML here so it says
关键是在XML中，所以它说
sign up process okay and I'm gonna do so
好的注册过程，我要这样做
with some some process variables right
有一些过程变量
so I'm gonna say I want to give it a map
所以我要说给我一张地图
of data okay so what is this time to get
数据还可以，那么这次要获得什么
i D good
我很好
okay that'll be the idea to process him
好吧，那将是处理他的想法
since idea basically now we're gonna
因为基本上现在我们要
give it some context some variables that
给它一些上下文一些变量
will propagate those are the process
将传播那些是过程
variables that are unique to this
唯一的变量
process instance so I'm gonna say a map
流程实例，所以我要说一张地图
dot oh I should have specified them well
点哦，我应该指定好它们
it doesn't matter let's just do this
没关系，让我们这样做
with Java I can if I had to specify Java
使用Java我可以，如果我必须指定Java
Lebanon the neutralizer I would have
黎巴嫩我要的中和剂
been able to save myself a little bit of
能够救自己一点点
tedium here but whatever long as you
乏味，但只要你
knew hashmap long its dot put customer
知道哈希图的长点在于客户
ID customer ID email and you know I
ID客户ID电子邮件，您知道我
might even benefit from ID okay and
甚至可以从ID正常中受益，并且
good so there's that okay
好，那没关系
that's across this instance and I'm
在这个实例中，我
gonna provide those variables there and
在那里提供那些变量，
those will be maintained along with the
这些将与
graph itself for the process instance
图本身为流程实例
okay now had I used Java eleven I
好吧，现在我使用Java 11
couldn't save our VARs equals new
无法保存我们的VAR等于新
hashmap and I could have even used the
哈希图，我什至可以使用
new map that builder in a map of but I
新的地图，但在我的地图生成器
didn't I'm paying that price hopefully
我不是希望为此付出代价
that should give you a reason to upgrade
那应该给你升级的理由
okay so we've got now these easy to use
好，所以我们现在有了这些易于使用的
constants private static final not that
常量私有静态最终不是
same okay there's my constant variables
同样，有我的常量变量
so I'm going to begin the process let's
所以我要开始这个过程，让我们
see what that looks like before we get
在我们得到之前先看一下是什么样
further down the line let's just see
再往下走，让我们看看
what that looks like okay so run
看起来怎么样，所以运行
already check out the process instance
已经签出流程实例
above that highlighted line it says
在突出显示的行上方，它说
process instance ID so that worked good
流程实例ID，因此效果很好
so there's now a running process of
所以现在有一个正在运行的过程
course it's h2 so just as soon as the
当然是h2，所以只要
application shut down all the process
应用程序关闭所有过程
State and all the data that was gone
状态和所有丢失的数据
could sit in memory embedded database
可以坐在内存嵌入式数据库中
but you could use postcards or whatever
但您可以使用明信片或其他任何东西
you know durable database
你知道持久数据库
okay now we've got that now we are by
好吧，现在我们知道了
definition at that state where we have
我们在那个州的定义
those tasks so here we can use the
这些任务，所以在这里我们可以使用
process task service to do a task query
处理任务服务以执行任务查询
to find where we have active tasks where
查找我们在哪里有活跃任务
a process variable called customer ID PV
一个称为客户ID PV的过程变量
is equal to customer ID include that and
等于客户ID，包括和
then get a list right okay and we could
然后得到正确的列表，我们可以
we could go a step further we could say
我们可以走得更远，可以说
task name and the task name here of
任务名称和此处的任务名称
course is confirm email tasks
当然是确认电子邮件任务
[Music]
[音乐]
what does that give us well that gives
那给我们带来的好处是什么
us tasks these are the list of tasks
我们的任务这些是任务列表
objects that we can poke at we can say
我们可以戳的物体可以说
okay well equals assert wrong a search
好吧等于等于断言搜索错误
no kidding okay so where do we put a
没有开玩笑吧，所以我们在哪里放
search there this
在这里搜索
let's search is ah I was about this
让我们搜索是啊，我是关于这个
confused and the message is only left I
困惑，消息只剩下我
knew I was off I knew that was a little
知道我不在，我知道那有点
weirder here I always get those confused
我在这里总是很奇怪
okay so now past claiming completing now
好吧，现在过去声称现在完成了
here you as you can imagine we've got a
您可以想象在这里，我们有一个
bit of a race condition I I could claim
种族条件II可能声称
this but I'm not gonna I could say okay
这个，但我不会说好
let's well first I want to confirm that
首先让我们确认一下
tasks dot size is equal to one right
任务点大小等于一右
because we don't want to have more than
因为我们不想拥有超过
one tastic right so there should be one
一项权利，所以应该有一项
outstanding actually you could vary you
杰出的，实际上你可以改变你
know like let's think about that let's
知道，让我们考虑一下，让我们
say that somebody by accident started
说有人偶然开始
the signup process twice and so now
注册过程两次，所以现在
there's two different outstanding
有两个不同的优秀
processes that have arrived at this
达到这个目的的过程
state well you know you should get them
说好，你知道你应该得到他们
all and complete them absolutely so you
全部并完全完成它们，所以您
could say finally my test name that's
最终可以说我的测试名称是
the sign of this customer and then
该客户的标志，然后
completely I know there's only one right
完全我知道只有一种权利
now so that's what I'm trying to prove
现在，这就是我要证明的
I'm trying to prove that we can actually
我试图证明我们可以
do let's do a better job assert true
让我们做得更好断言是真的
there we want to assert that it's
我们要断言这是
greater than 1 greater than equal to one
大于1大于等于1
ok so let's try that
好的，让我们尝试一下
okay I've got something so task name
好吧，我有东西，所以任务名称
task ID
任务ID
oh that's the name okay whoops
哦，那是好的，哇！
I think it's a task definite definition
我认为这是一个明确的任务
ID that's what I wanted that's if that
那就是我想要的ID
fails otherwise I think it's I think the
失败，否则我认为这是我认为
task name is the other string yeah let's
任务名称是另一个字符串，是的
try it or I could just go back and do
试试吧，否则我就回去做
the right thing here okay take to that
这里正确的事情可以
one failed let's try one more time and
一个失败了，让我们再尝试一次，
this goes here
这去这里
makes it more consistent anyway when I
无论如何，当我使它更加一致时
do that oh there should be one
这样做哦应该有一个
outstanding what do I have if not one
杰出的，如果没有我该怎么办
let's see
让我们来看看
what if that makes a difference
如果那有所作为怎么办
No
没有
debug time
调试时间
tasks is empty
任务为空
oh oh I'm not sure if I need that
哦，哦，我不确定是否需要
actually
其实
did I let's see a task name something
我有看到任务名称吗
like that that should be fairly
这样，应该是相当
straightforward
直截了当
okay there we go that fixed it so now we
好吧，我们去修复它了，所以现在我们
are we have a we have gotten to the
我们有一个我们已经到了
place where we have a list of tasks okay
我们有任务列表的地方
and when once we have a list of tasks
当我们有了任务清单时
what we want to do is complete them and
我们要做的就是完成它们，
so here we can use the task service to
所以在这里我们可以使用任务服务
complete right so get outstanding tasks
正确完成任务
now complete outstanding tasks and you
现在完成未完成的任务，您
know easiest way to do it is to say for
知道最简单的方法是说
each task and we can now save some data
每个任务，我们现在可以保存一些数据
so we say this task service got complete
所以我们说这个任务服务已经完成了
task ID so there's the ID right
任务ID，所以ID正确
you might also do this dot tasks service
您可能还会执行此点任务服务
dr. claim here you gonna say I'm gonna
博士声称在这里你会说我会
task this ID is gonna be claimed by me
我要索取这个ID的任务
Jayla or you could use the spring
Jayla或您可以使用Spring
security Java security principle target
安全Java安全原则目标
name or whatever right and then you
名称或其他权利，然后您
would would complete it right so and the
会正确完成它，所以
reason you would claim it is because you
你会声称这是因为你
don't want somebody else in a sort of
不想别人
race condition you know you might have a
您知道自己可能有一个种族状况
like a a pool of people like an Amazon
就像一群人，像亚马逊
Mechanical Turk you might have a pool of
机械特克，您可能会
people looking at a screen where our
人们看着屏幕上
there's outstanding work to do and they
有要做的杰出工作，他们
might start the tap they might start
可能会开始水龙头，他们可能会开始
trying to you know finish the task that
试图让你知道完成任务
is out there while you're trying to
当你试图去那里
finish it to here you can claim it so
完成到这里，你可以要求它
that it's no longer accessible no longer
不再访问
get nobody can can take it for example
让任何人都可以拿它为例
okay and then once you've done that what
好吧，然后一旦完成
do we want to do well at this point once
我们现在想做好一次吗
we've come once we've completed that
完成后我们就来了
confirm that the email has been sent
确认电子邮件已发送
because it's gonna produce automatically
因为它会自动产生
from the task where it was waiting to
从等待的任务到
the email task and it's gonna then end
电子邮件任务，然后将结束
up at the end event so we should see it
在结束事件，所以我们应该看到它
automatically go from the completion of
从完成自动开始
this all the way down to the end
一直到最后
immediately right in the same
立即就在同一位置
transaction in fact so we go now to our
交易事实上，所以我们现在去我们的
test one more time
再测试一次
I'm going to inject our email service
我要注入我们的电子邮件服务
which wasn't much of an email service at
这不是电子邮件服务的主要来源
all
所有
he was it so on a wired private email
在有线私人电子邮件中，他是如此
service and when use email service just
服务以及何时使用电子邮件服务
took just to confirm a search and again
只是为了确认搜索而已
this is a one of those things that could
这是那些可以
probably have done with mock beam this
可能已经用模拟光束完成了
dot email service dot sends dot get and
点电子邮件服务点发送点获取和
what do we say that data was being
我们说数据是什么
stored an email service customer ID now
现在存储了电子邮件服务的客户ID
it's email okay its email so we are
这是电子邮件，可以，因此我们
going to confirm that this email is a
确认这封电子邮件是
key
键
cert equals email dot get one okay that
证书等于电子邮件点得到一个好的
should be the same uh and that's it
应该是一样的，就是这样
that's that that should be the whole
那就是全部
process let's try and run this now
过程让我们尝试并立即运行
there we go look at that so we have now
在那里我们去看看，所以我们现在
started the process instance we sent the
启动了流程实例，我们发送了
welcome email you can see it printed
欢迎电子邮件，您可以看到它已打印
that out and now it's shutting down
出来，现在它正在关闭
right that's the whole thing the whole
对，这就是全部
thing is done and at this point if I
事情已经完成，在这一点上，如果我
even if I ran it one to find that data I
即使我运行它来找到该数据我
couldn't I that did it
我不能那样做吗
that process has been you know executed
这个过程已经被你知道执行了
it's not deleted if you if we had my
如果您有我们的话，它不会被删除
sequel or postcards or something durable
续集或明信片或其他耐用物品
we could log into the tables and we
我们可以登录表格，然后
could see that that data is still there
可以看到数据仍然存在
and indeed we could even inject the
实际上我们甚至可以注入
process engine for example private
处理引擎，例如私有的
process engine that's right or we can
正确的流程引擎，或者我们可以
get the history service right we can use
获得我们可以使用的历史服务
the history service to say okay well you
历史服务说你还好
know let's create a historic process
知道让我们创造一个历史性的过程
instance query where I can search for
我可以在其中查询的实例查询
process you know variable value include
您知道变量值包括的过程
you know customer ID equals to one right
您知道客户ID等于一项权利
I can do that and I can look at the old
我可以做到，我可以看看旧的
processes but it's no longer a current
流程，但不再是最新的
on you know active process so it gets
在你知道活跃的过程，所以它得到
you have to find it through the history
您必须通过历史找到它
service so this is I think you know just
服务，所以这是我想你知道的
the beginning we've only looked at just
一开始我们只看了
a smallest bit of of what this API can
这个API可以做的一小部分
do workflow solutions are great for long
工作流程解决方案长期适用
running tasks in which you must involve
运行您必须参与的任务
both humans and autonomous agents you
无论是人类还是自治代理
can see it embeds nicely in a Springwood
可以看到它很好地嵌入了Springwood中
application but there's so much more to
应用程序，但还有更多
this than what I've shown you here and
比我在这里给你看的
so it's for this reason that big
所以正因为如此大
customers are flocking left and right to
客户蜂拥而至
buy the flowable product because it
购买流动产品，因为它
gives you identity management gives you
给你身份管理给你
integration with enterprise it gives you
与企业集成，可为您提供
a whole bunch more than just this this
一大堆不只是这个
these pieces here right you get an
这些零件在这里，你会得到一个
actual fully fledged server that you can
您可以使用的完全成熟的服务器
use to solve this problems solve you
用解决这个问题解决你
know kinds of document management
知道各种文件管理
problems to solve these kinds of things
解决这类问题的问题
beyond what I've shown you here I hope
希望我在这里没有向您展示过
you got something out of this and
你从中得到了一些东西
obviously a I really am I really do hope
显然，我真的是我真的希望
I can do another video in this or
我可以在其中制作另一个视频或
something I mean I just feel like the
我的意思是我只是觉得
case stuff is so cool I know
箱子的东西太酷了，我知道
a fairly new feature oh there's been so
一个相当新的功能哦
much that's happened in the last couple
在过去的两件事中发生了很多事情
of years it's now a it's now a 300
几年来现在是300
person plus strong company that powers
人加强大的公司
this that that drives engineering work
这推动了工程工作
on this so it's moving very quickly it's
因此它的移动速度非常快
an amazing group I'm just great eager to
我非常渴望一个很棒的团队
see where things go I think this has
看看事情要去哪里，我认为这已经
more relevance in the world of micro
在微型世界中更具相关性
services and than ever before and it
服务，比以往任何时候都更
certainly has relevance in a world where
在这个世界中无疑具有相关性
things are more complex than ever before
事情比以往更复杂
so I hope you got something out of it as
所以我希望你从中得到一些东西
always I want to thank you for watching
我总是要感谢你的收看
and we'll see
我们会看到
you
您